Jonathan Zachary

jontzachary@gmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/jon-zachary/ Github: github.com/Jon-zachary Phone: (917) 771-1146
Web Developer

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with a passion for creative problem solving. 20+ years as a chess educator combined with a lifelong interest in coding have instilled in me both the skills it takes to engineer solutions with clean, maintainable code as well as a passion for communicating those solutions to a wide audience.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Node, Express, React, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, R

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly -

Feb. 2017 - Present

Instructional Associate

- Lectured on HTML/CSS/JavaScript as well as React, SQL, Node and general programming concepts
- Mentored students, managed student projects and helped tailor curriculum
- Provided logistic support for instructional team and liaised with instructor managers.

General Assembly -

Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2017

Web Development Immersive

A Three month immersive teaching developers the fundamentals of full stack web development focused primarily on HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Node, Express and Rails.

<u>projects</u>

- **BookNote:** A platform agnostic persistent note taking app that keeps your notes in one place and arranged by text and page. Made with HTML,CSS,React and Firebase.
- 2018 World Chess Championship app: Lets a user play through the games of the 2018 FIDE world chess championship. There is a board to play out the moves plus four information panels. It is written in React and styled with flexbox and is responsive.
- Conway's Game Of Life: A vanilla javascript implementation of John Conway's game of life. The app is styled with css grid.

Chess Instructor - New York, New York

1999 - Present

- Chess consultant for two episodes of NBC's "Madam Secretary"
- Tailored lessons to skill level and client goals. High-profile students have included Kevin Klein and Don Imus
- Provided classroom instruction for various organizations including the August Aichorn Center, a residential treatment facility for underprivileged youth
- Led after-school chess programs, most recently at St. Luke's School in the West Village

Chess Forum - New York, New York

May 1999 - 2016

Store Manager

- Responsible for the sales team at New York's premier chess retail and culture store
- Led staffing, training, bookkeeping, and event planning

EDUCATION

General Assembly - 2017 Web Development Immersive Reed College - Mathematics